Vianey Garcia

UX Designer / Visual Design Lead

Los Angeles • vianeygarcia.design@gmail.com • (661) 675-6053 • linkedin.com/in/vianey-garcia • vianeygarcia.com

OBJECTIVE:

A resourceful creative with a background in the visual arts and a proven ability to apply design thinking to develop intuitive and engaging products. Dedicated to human-centered design, aiming to explore, cultivate relationships, and create meaningful experiences.

ACCOMPLISHMENTS:

- Led the UX design for the AltaMed Health Services Workforce Recruitment landing page, attracting over 100,000 visitors and accumulating 150,000 views, resulting in 66,000 clicks to the Workday application website.
- Awarded first place of 29 submissions in Next Shift Learning & Snap Inc.'s U.S. Snap Lens Challenge 2022. Designed and developed an Augmented Reality lens with 2,500+ views & 120+ shares in Lens Studio.
- Recognized by leadership to lead an all-male team of 3, including a developer and 3D designer, for our final project focused on educating pre-teen girls about women in STEM. Oversaw project management deadlines, assets, and delivery of the final AR lens, garnering 84,000+ views and 250+ shares.

TOOLS:

Adobe Creative Suite (InDesign, Photoshop, Illustrator, After Effects, AdobeXD), Lens Studio, Blender, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Figma, Invision, Unbounce, Miro, Notion, Slack, Figjam, G Suite, Microsoft Office (Word, excel, PowerPoint).

DESIGN SKILLS:

User-Centered Design, Wireframes, User Flows, Design Thinking, Rapid Prototyping, Field Research, Interviews, Personas, Journey Mapping, Storyboarding, Product Design, User Interface Design, Usability Testing, Motion Graphics.

EXPERIENCE:

Sensis Agency Los Angeles, CA

UX Design Intern

July 2023 - December 2023

- Led the UX design for the AltaMed Health Services Workforce Recruitment sites, attracting over 100,000 visitors and accumulating 150,000 views to the landing page, resulting in 66,000 clicks to the Workday application website resulting in a 30% surge in qualified recruitment candidates, bolstering the talent pipeline for critical roles.
- Collaborated closely with Product Managers and developers to conceptualize and prepare deliverables, including content plans, journey maps, wireframes, and prototypes, utilizing Figma and Unbounce.
- Embraced an iterative design process, used presentation skills to develop slides to communicate design concepts to cross-functional teams and stakeholders, and incorporated feedback to refine designs throughout development.

UX Designer / Augmented Reality Designer

Los Angeles, CA

Freelance

Nov 2022 - July 2023

- Implemented color theory, typography and user centered design practices to develop digital products for clients, such as websites, branded content, UI elements and AR concepts using Figma, Lens Studio, Blender, and Adobe Creative Suite.
- Created wireframes, storyboards, design systems, prototypes, established brand identity, graphic assets, style guide, layout, animations and visual designs to articulate digital and AR concepts.
- Collaborated with clients to define design vision, scope of work, and deliverable timeframes. Iterated based on feedback, enhancing design elements, creative direction and visual consistency.

Snap Inc. / Next Shift Learning

Los Angeles, CA

Snap Lens Scholar

Jun 2022 - Aug 2022

- Engineered 10+ interactive AR experiences for Snapchat using Lens Studio, Blender, Photoshop, Illustrator, After Effects, and Javascript, incorporating 2D and 3D graphics resulting in over 70,000 total shares.
- Applied design thinking and collaborated in teams of 3 during weekly hackathons, delivering interactive and engaging lenses by deadlines ranging from 1 hour to a week.
- Recognized by leadership to lead a team of 3 for a capstone AR project focused on STEM education. Oversaw project management deadlines, assets creation, and delivery, garnering 84,000+ views and 250+ shares.

Grand Games - Student Project, Santa Monica College

Santa Monica, CA

UX Designer and Researcher

Sep 2021 - Nov 2021

• Collected in-depth user research through observation, interviews, surveys, and testing with 20+ customers. Identified key UX pain points, leading to a complete redesign.

- Communicated concepts and insights to stakeholders from Grand Park L.A. and VeryNice design studio using sketches, storyboards, and prototypes presented via Google Slides, resulting in 6 iterations.
- Applied design thinking to align user desires with technical feasibility and business viability.

Wayve - Student Project, Santa Monica College

Santa Monica, CA

UX Designer and Researcher

Sep 2020 - Dec 2020

- Collected qualitative and quantitative user research through observation, interviews, and surveys with 10+ public transit passengers and bus operators extracting and interpreting data, applying empathy and accessible design to shape user personas, journey maps, and wireframes.
- Developed and usability tested prototypes, ranging from low-fidelity paper prototypes to high-fidelity Figma prototypes resulting in 4 iterations.
- Applied a narrative with digital illustrations into a vision video created in Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop, and After Effects to present the problem, insights, and solution, integrating the brand identity and product style guide.

Taunt Global - Student Project, Santa Monica College

Santa Monica, CA

Web Design

Apr 2020

- Engineered a responsive website for a fictional company using HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, and jQuery.
- Conceptualized the entire website from scratch, establishing brand identity, graphic assets, style guide, and animations.
- Integrated time and file management systems to organize work, ensuring the execution of project deadlines within the 2 week timeframe.

Home Health Care Aid Los Angeles, CA

Freelance Health Care Aid

Mar 2013 - Feb 2018

- Administered care, executed meals, distributed medication, and provided assistance with quality of life care for 2 patients.
- Implemented a process to streamline patient tasks, including scheduling, paperwork, organization, and medical visits.
- Demonstrated empathy towards patients by actively listening and offering emotional support while effectively communicating medical information.

Museum Intern Arcata, CA

The Natural History Museum of Cal Poly Humboldt

Feb 2012- June 2012

- Assisted in the curation and installation of 3 exhibits, including artifact preparation and display design, to enhance educational and visual impact for museum visitors.
- Developed promotional materials, including fliers and bus advertisements to market museum exhibitions.
- Conducted research and compiled information on natural history subjects, contributing to the development of accurate and engaging exhibit content and educational materials.

Cal Poly Humboldt Arcata, CA

Gallery Attendant

Aug 2011- June 2012

- Managed daily gallery operations, including opening and closing duties, handling sales transactions, and providing visitors with detailed information, enhancing their overall experience and understanding of the exhibits.
- Supervised the preservation, proper documentation, and aesthetic integrity of over 50 art pieces within the gallery.
- Supported museum operations by cataloging artifacts, and updating databases, ensuring accurate documentation and inventory management.

CERTIFICATIONS:

Museum and Gallery Practices

Arcata, CA

- Developed expertise in museological theory, curatorial strategies, and the historical development of museums and galleries through comprehensive and immersive coursework.
- Executed exhibition design, preparation, and programming by curating and installing exhibits at the Goudi'ni Native American Arts and Reese Bullen Galleries, including supervising exhibits, facilitating art sales, and maintaining accurate records of transactions and proceeds.
- Administered the maintenance, curation, installation, and deinstallation of exhibits within the HSU Art Department Permanent Collection, ensuring meticulous care, documentation, preservation, and aesthetic integrity of the gallery space.

EDUCATION:

Santa Monica College

Santa Monica, CA

Bachelor of Science, Major in Interaction Design

2019 - 2022

Cal Poly Humboldt Arcata, CA

Bachelor of Art, Major in Studio Art; Minor in Business Administration

2008 - 2012